Previously on Gotham...
Did Walker destroy Haven?
EDUARDO: This part of
the op is need-to-know.
I come bearing gifts.
Reunification with the mainland
hangs on by a thread.
Toxic chemicals rain down
onto the city, and the government
cuts us adrift for good.
THOMPKINS: The filtration system
that Lucius designed is working.
LUCIUS: It's not glamorous work,
but we are helping to save
the lives of thousands of people.
SELINA: You're leaving Gotham.
OSWALD: I believe
the time has come
for a change of scenery.
You found a way out of Gotham?
It's a submarine.
OSWALD: Jim Gordon and
Lee Thompkins are man and wife.
He will never see
you as anything but
a dangerous woman
keeping his child
from him.
Eduardo.
Walker.
Professor Strange'll have
you fixed up in no time.
(whirring)
(labored breathing)
WALKER: Rest easy, Eduardo.
I made you a promise
when I found you
in that hole in Peña Dura.
And I intend to keep it.
To give you a true purpose
and the strength
to see it through.
However, I'm afraid this process
will be agonizing
and, unfortunately,
quite lengthy.
Apologies in advance.
(squeaking)
(labored breathing)
You're going to be reborn.
And then you'll be
the bane of the unjust.
The bane of the corrupt.
The bane of anyone
who opposes us.
(screaming)
Radio confirmation.
General Wade's
landing craft docked.
His convoy's on
the way here now.
Reunification day is today.
Harv, that is great
news, but then what?
Just 'cause we
rebuild some bridges
doesn't mean things are
gonna suddenly improve.
So, uh, future got you spooked?
(sighs) Yeah, I guess.
I mean, I want to believe
things are gonna get better,
but sometimes it's just hard
for me to see it, you know.
Can't say I understand.
I don't have kids, at
least none that I know of.
But you got one coming,
so we got no
choice but to believe.
It's got to be better than what
we've been through, right?
It damn well better be.
Seven days in a row of
.07 water toxicity levels.
Lucius' filters did the job.
Eh, good work.
Hope it's not wasted.
Is there a reason to
think there's a problem?
Jim's got a lot on his mind.
What with Gotham
rejoining the world
and a baby coming
into the world next week.
Give it a rest, Harvey.
All joking aside.
We're here because
of you. Mm-hmm.
And you're gonna be a
father. That's a future I'll take.
Over the past year,
you've all done good work.
We've made Gotham a safe
place for kids and families.
We've given people the food
and medicine they needed.
But it's not over yet.
So, no matter what
General Wade says today,
the work continues.
Give yourselves one
more round of applause.
And get back to work.
Here they come.
Captain Gordon.
Nice to finally meet
you in the flesh.
General, welcome to Gotham.
Good that you've
reestablished some semblance
of law and order around here.
Seems like the Green Zone
stretches to every
corner of the island.
General, Wayne Labs
show toxicity levels
way below the threshold
the government set for us.
All due respect, Mr. Wayne,
but I got to go with what
my people tell me on this.
♪♪♪♪
Cutting it a little
close, aren't we?
Is that under 27 pounds,
13 ounces?
It can't possibly make
that big a difference.
It's only the difference
between getting off this island
or sinking to the
bottom of the river.
Well, then Pengy can off-load
a few of his knickknacks.
Not a chance.
Because you know what's
worth its weight in gold?
- Gold.
- Ah!
(groaning)
Congratulations!
(chuckles)
Go to the clinic.
Go have your baby.
What? So the two
of you can hightail it
off this rock without
me? I don't think so.
I assure you we will
not launch without you.
Ed and I will finish
making preparations
and we will be ready to launch
the moment you get back here
with that little bundle of joy.
Or unless I should
drive you to the clinic
in light of your
delicate condition?
I can do it. I'm
not that delicate.
Remember that if you even think
about double-crossing me.
It's very kind of you
to offer to drive her.
I knew she would
never accept my help.
Should I start the engine?
One less passenger
to worry about.
Oh, two, actually.
You are so right.
(chuckles)
(gasps, chuckles)
Found it.
Ah, well done, Miss Kyle.
All right, let's have a look.
Uh, here we are.
Oh, so this guy's the architect
who designed Wayne Manor?
Yes, right.
With the reunification, a new
Wayne Manor must follow.
And it'll be just
like the old one?
Oh, nothing is just like it was.
So why are we
looking at the old plans?
Perhaps I'm not ready
to let go of the past.
Well, if it makes
you feel better,
I wish I could blow up my past.
Well, maybe you will.
One day, when you
build something new,
the past will
always be part of it.
As for me,
now Master Bruce is grown,
building a new manor might
be my last great service to him.
A home.
And then what?
You retire?
No.
I will stand guard,
as I've always done.
I thought this was all settled.
This is bull.
My results are accurate, Jim.
BULLOCK: We don't know this
general. Maybe he's with Walker.
Let's not get carried away.
Bruce, go and check on the tech.
(radio crackles)
(sighs)
This is Gordon.
THOMPKINS: It's Lee.
Everything okay?
Barbara just showed up here,
in labor.
You're kidding.
THOMPKINS: You
better come quick.
Are you okay?
Yeah. Yeah.
I'll try to get over
there as soon as I can.
Try to.
Um... try to wait for me.
It doesn't really work that way.
I know.
Okay.
Wait.
I love you.
(labored breathing)
I love you, too.
Jim!
What? What's wrong?
We did it.
You did it. We
got through it, Jim.
WADE: Captain.
All clear.
Congratulations.
Reunification can begin.
Well, I'm glad I can
make you so happy.
Funny thing is, sir,
that's just the second
best news I've gotten today.
(distant rumble)
What's that?
(bang)
- Jim.
- Incoming.
Everybody get back!
Get inside! Get inside!
Go, go.
(gunfire)
(grunting)
(bones crunch)
(man screaming)
Eduardo?
Not anymore.
All right, people, listen up.
I want squads headed
for Knights Stadium,
Yeavley Park, and
Granton Station.
Work your way out. We
got to find him, people.
Bloody hell happened?
Seems that Jim's old army buddy
wasn't quite as
dead as we'd hoped.
I got squads covering
the north side.
They're sweeping from Coventry
down to Miller Harbor,
but they could be anywhere.
Well, give us an area to search
- and we'll get
it covered.
- Uh...
Take Reatton,
work your way to
South City Park.
Looks like you're not done
protecting Bruce yet, Alfred.
(rasping)
Eduardo.
What did Walker do to you?
When I was in Peña
Dura prison, Jim,
the guards played a game.
They'd choose one of us...
and they buried us alive.
They'd take bets on whether
you could dig your way out.
But then they'd bury you deeper.
And play again.
I was the champion.
To survive that...
I had to stop being human.
I had to become...
something else.
I became Bane.
Only I didn't know it yet.
But she knew and she
showed me the way.
If the world is
full of monsters,
the only way to defeat them...
is to become one yourself.
I'm sorry.
You were a good soldier.
Hmm.
Don't pity me, Jim.
We are building the future.
She's given me a
purity of mission.
And unlike the army,
she is willing to
carry things out.
A new world is coming.
Strong...
merciless...
unyielding.
I've heard it all before.
Not gonna happen.
And how are you
going to stop me, Jim?
Not me.
You kidnapped Bruce Wayne
and a general of the U.S. Army.
You talk about your future,
Eduardo, but you don't have one.
But Eduardo's dead, Jim.
There is only Bane now.
(door opens)
Rise.
I said rise!
WALKER: Not so formal.
Captain and I are acquainted.
Get the other one.
I recognize your voice,
but I don't know
what to call you.
I know it's not Walker.
So who are you?
That's a good question.
Perhaps Bruce Wayne can
help us figure that one out.
(footsteps approach)
You okay?
(panting): Yeah.
You want hostages?
You've got me and a
general of the U.S. Army.
Let him go.
This has nothing to do with him.
"This has nothing
to do with him"?
But, Captain, you don't
even know what "this" is.
This, everything
I have done here,
is about punishing Gotham.
For the sins of Bruce Wayne.
You can start now.
No... no!
(grunts, groans)
And again.
(grunts)
So...
Bruce Wayne.
I'm thinking of a name.
Can you guess whose it is?
What?
Wrong. And again.
(shouts)
Want to take another guess?
Farewell, my beloved Gotham.
City of my birth.
Parting is such sweet sorrow.
Though I leave you today...
my heart will always remain.
I do so hate goodbyes.
Well, you're in luck.
- We're not going anywhere.
- What are you
talking about?
Engine won't start; pressure
regulator valve's missing.
Or rather it's stolen.
Barbara!
(exhaling heavily)
Blood pressure's normal.
I'm glad something
about this is normal.
So how long's this gonna
take, Doc, soup to nuts?
Are you in a hurry or something?
No, it's just that, uh...
I just feel like you've been...
so great about this, and,
you know, it's been
awkward as hell for you,
and... I haven't even
really said thank you.
I don't expect a thank
you from you, Barbara.
Then perhaps the best
thank you would be for me
to get out of here
as soon as possible.
Whatever's on your mind...
the health of the
baby comes first.
I know that.
So, long haul or
short, we're here.
Until you have a healthy
baby in your arms.
That's all I want.
(softly): Okay.
(exhales sharply)
- (grunts)
- Stop it!
A name, a person.
The reason this
is all happening.
Can't you guess yet?
I don't know!
If you want to
punish me, then do it.
Hurt me, not him.
I am hurting you.
- (panting)
- There's nothing
more painful
than seeing your friends suffer.
But he's more
than just a friend,
isn't he, Bruce?
Jim Gordon's been
like a father to you.
Oh.
How awful it must be to
watch another father die.
(strained exhale)
Who am I doing this for?
Say the name.
(grunts)
(groans)
When the ones you love die...
it's like a part of
yourself is cut off...
forever.
(sobs)
You know that.
So why do I hate you so much?
Who was cut away from me?
Last chance.
(whimpers)
Yes.
Now you know.
Say his name.
Say it.
Ra's al Ghul.
This is revenge for his death.
And who am I?
You're his daughter.
My name is Nyssa al Ghul.
And revenge is just the
beginning of what I want.
(Bane rasping)
NYSSA: The League of
Shadows is everywhere.
Did you think my father's
mission would die with him?
Humankind will be
purged of weakness.
I'm just starting
with you and yours.
You're right.
I killed Ra's.
So whatever you need to do...
do it to me.
No.
You can't take all the
blame for killing my father.
I mean, you did
have some help, right?
Someone who quite literally
gave you a helping hand.
- What are you doing?
- (yells)
Well done, Barbara.
Go get Barbara Kean.
Eduardo...
She's pregnant.
She's carrying a child.
A child.
One soul's future
weighed against the world's.
Your concern seems petty, Jim.
If he touches a hair
on that child's head,
I will destroy
everything you have.
I don't have anything left,
just my father's mission.
Bane wants you to
join that mission with us.
To see the world as he sees it.
- Never.
- STRANGE:
Never say never,
- Captain Gordon.
- No!
NYSSA: How does it feel, Bruce,
knowing that all
of this is your fault?
Tell me. I'd
really like to know.
(screams)
(groaning)
There must be something
you can give me.
We're out of the
drugs that you need.
It's okay. You're almost there.
I'll get you some ice chips
so you don't get dehydrated.
Gee, thanks.
Lee.
Ed.
Don't worry, I'm
not here for you.
But for the record,
you stabbed me first.
If you two are quite done,
we are actually
here for Barbara.
Or more precisely,
what she stole from us.
I don't know what this
is about, and I don't care.
You two need to get
out of here right now.
(chuckles) Gladly.
Just as soon as Barbara
gives us the...
What's it called?
- Pressure regulator valve.
- Right.
That.
(sighs)
I should have known that
you would try to screw us over.
You only noticed because
you tried to screw me over first.
Second, technically.
Okay, she's in the
middle of having a baby.
And we are in
the middle of trying
to leave Gotham,
and we can't do that
without a crucial
part of the submarine
which will ferry us
all away from here!
That's why you
were in such a rush
- to get out of here.
- As are we.
Hand over the part... now.
Don't point that at the baby.
What? No, I did not!
I... I was merely trying
to make a general
threatening gesture
with a firearm.
But you did, though. You
pointed the gun at the baby.
All right, fine. I'm sorry!
Now give us what we want!
No! You think I'm stupid
enough to have the part on me?
It's hidden away,
somewhere safe.
And if you think you can
torture me into telling you where,
there is literally
nothing more painful
than what I am going
through right now!
(explosion)
(screaming in distance)
NURSE: Hey, you
stay out of here.
This is a hospital.
(neck snaps)
(bell dings)
Barbara Kean,
your time is up.
There's no place
for you to hide.
No one will save you.
No mercy that will spare you.
You simply cannot
run from your sins.
And you cannot run from me.
What do you want from me?
(chuckles)
Let me let you in on
a little military secret.
It's called Special Order 386.
In the event that Gotham
is irretrievably lost,
a contingency plan
was put in place
to reduce the city to rubble.
No.
There are still
innocent people here.
You asked me
what I want from you.
I want you to
suffer, Bruce Wayne.
And then I want you to die.
Spend a little time
with that thought.
We'll be starting soon.
♪♪♪♪
- Who are those guys?
- No idea.
Exactly how many people
have you screwed over?
Present company excluded.
There are 79 people
in this building.
Well, fortunately, they seem
to only be trying to kill one.
So, by all means, let's
gather 'round the target.
- All right.
- (groaning)
Maybe we can cut
through the abandoned wing
and we can get to the
ambulance bay that way.
Might take some time, but...
Oh, if only there were
two able-bodied men
who could buy us some.
And why, pray tell, should
we risk our necks for you?
(straining): Chivalry?
(laughs)
But if that's too much,
remember, if I die,
you will never
find that sub part.
Fine.
We'll keep them busy.
We'll meet you at the docks.
Thank you.
- What?
- Keep them busy?
I only brought enough
ammunition for a light firefight,
not to repel a
paramilitary assault.
What should we use, bedpans?
I was actually
thinking of something
a little more... flammable.
♪♪♪♪
(both laugh)
(grunts)
Why, Captain Gordon,
how nice that you're awake.
You picked the
losing side, Strange.
The army's coming
to Gotham. Help me,
and you can do what you do best:
survive.
I happen to think more
of Ms. al Ghul's
chances for success
than a man in your...
well...
position.
You really think she can
take on the entire army?
As a matter of fact, I do.
With my help.
You are just a few
modifications away
from being a mighty
soldier in her forces.
Not unlike your
friend, Eduardo...
I will help you to
realize your full potential,
give you true strength.
I'll pass.
Consent is hardly
a prerequisite.
We will begin...
with, uh, physical improvements.
(groans softly)
Sorry.
And finish...
with certain mental adjustments.
(elevator bell dings)
(rasping)
(cheers)
(Bane rasping)
Your contractions are
about a minute apart.
We've got to get
you out of here.
(screams)
(grunts)
(pained yelling)
Nice shot!
(yelling)
Keep breathing.
(panting)
(grunts quietly)
♪♪♪♪
(panting softly)
Some try to hide,
some try to cheat.
- (sighs)
- But time will
let us always meet.
What am I?
- Pregnant lady with a gun?
- Death.
But close enough.
So, where to now?
Well, I believe...
we have a sub to catch.
- (chuckles)
- How long have you had that?
Long enough to know she'd
never let it out of her sight.
(laughs)
And you stuck around long enough
to risk both of our
lives to save Barbara's?
Or was it to protect Lee?
Do you want me to answer that or
do you want sail away from here?
Bon voyage.
Oh, those bastards have
stolen the damn sub part!
You mean, stole it back.
Whose side are you on?
Clearly, I'm on the
baby's side, Barbara.
- Ooh!
- What was your plan, anyway?
You were going to be a fugitive
with Nygma and Penguin?
Well, I'm not exactly the stay-
at-home-and-bake-apple-pie type.
Yeah, running off on a submarine
seemed like a great alternative.
Barbara, you can live here.
You can have this baby here.
Jim is not taking the
baby away from you.
You really believe that?
You really think
Captain Jim Gordon
is gonna let a
criminal raise his kid?
People are already
shooting at my baby.
I have to protect him...
or her.
I have to be strong.
Right, being strong does not
mean you have to be a criminal.
Jim will help you.
And so will I if you'll let me.
Well, that's just weird.
I know.
Hey, baby, this
is your Auntie Lee.
Mommy tried to kill
her once, maybe twice.
- (both laugh)
- All right.
Okay, that's enough of that.
Come on. We got to keep moving.
I think this is happening now.
(screams)
(panting)
(whimpers softly)
(screams)
SOLDIER: What's
going on in there?
(yells)
This is Bruce Wayne.
Can anyone read me?
(grunts)
This is Bruce Wayne. Does
anyone at the GCPD read me?
This is Bruce Wayne.
Can anyone read me?
Bruce, it's Alfred. Where
the devil are you? Over.
Some abandoned
mansion in North Side Park.
- On my way.
- No.
I'll get out myself.
I need you to get to the clinic.
The clinic?
It's Ra's al Ghul's
daughter, Alfred.
She wants revenge. She
mutated Eduardo Dorrance
and sent him after Barbara.
Oh, gosh.
I'm fine.
I need you to get to
Barbara and the baby.
Now, you're going to
feel a slight discomfort.
That's the stimulant I've given
you to prepare your muscles.
You'll need it for what
comes next, which,
I'm afraid, is going
to be excruciating.
(machine whirring)
(grunts)
Do you feel that?
Yes.
(Gordon groans)
(grunts)
There's that fighting spirit
I've always admired so much.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
there's an alarm I must sound.
(grunts)
(panting)
- What the hell are you doing?
- Checking to make sure
Strange doesn't have one
of those chips in your head.
We need to hurry up,
get out of here before
he trips the alarm.
(alarm blaring)
Come on.
Alfred and GCPD are on their way
- to the clinic.
- Where's Nyssa?
I don't know.
But she's planning on using
the military to wipe out Gotham.
I can order them to stand down.
Then let's get you out of here.
THOMPKINS: She's beautiful.
Congratulations.
Hi, there.
Guess I'm-a have figure
out what to call you.
- (chuckles softly)
- (sniffles)
Thank you.
(baby crying)
- (Thompkins gasps)
- (tires screech)
- Come on.
- Get in the car now.
I'll hold him off.
SELINA: Alfred and I got this.
ALFRED: Selina, get in the car.
- Selina, get back in the car!
- No.
Go.
Oh, my, look at you.
You're a big'un, ain't you?
Bloody baby bully,
let's see what you got.
(grunting)
Dirty bastard.
(Alfred screams)
(grunting)
No!
Alfred.
(whispers): Alfred. No.
Somebody help!
(panting)
Somebody. Oh, no.
SOLDIER: A-ten-hut!
Welcome back, General.
Get me a secure line
to the mainland now.
Jim! Hey.
Just got word from Lee.
She and Barbara made
it out of the clinic okay.
And your baby daughter, too.
- Congratulations.
- They're going to The Sirens.
- You just had a baby girl,
brother. Say something.
- (laughs)
Just can't believe it.
We won, didn't we? It's over.
We did, and she's gonna have
a better world because of it.
She is. I promise.
Is Alfred with them?
Didn't say.
This is General Wade.
I am authorizing
Special Order 386.
No!
Gotham City is lost.
Begin your bombing
run on my order.
- Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
- Arrest them.
You can't do this.
Take them away.
You can't do this!
THOMPKINS: Okay, nice and slow.
(baby fussing)
(gasps)
- Barbara Kean.
- Run!
It's nice to finally meet you.
My name is Nyssa al Ghul.
I believe you knew my father.
I don't understand how the
general could have been chipped.
I didn't see a scar on the
back of his neck. Did you?
No. Strange must've hidden it.
Nyssa let us escape. She
knew we'd bring the general here
and do her dirty work for her.
BULLOCK: What now, Jim?
Son, if you're gonna
stick a gun in my face,
you should at least know
you're doing it wrong.
Come on, let's go.
(helicopter blades whirring)
(explosions)